all right we are live all right to our
new channel together tech Thank You
Adriel or setting it up so just start
off since this is not our first board
meeting but our first board meeting on
this channel I thought we could say what
together Tec is if anybody else would
like to do that you can step in or I can
try I definitely try I I'm guessing
we're wanting to start with sort of its
licensing oh you've got the echo oh yeah
no I cannot it had to mute because I it
was opening that you had YouTube open
background yeah alright um so together
Tech and it might actually help if we
all give our definition just to sort of
see where we're all at so how I think of
together tech can you start with is
going to sort of be a collection of
various projects we're together tech
itself is what we're calling the meta
project or the project to do with
projects where it's like I've got wiki
lecture and Bentley has reason score
yonis and forgetting the name of yours
conduct right conduct
thank you so the different sort of
challenges that we face with trying to
bring those kinds of projects oh you
know and actually from conception to
design building the audience to actually
getting a built to have frame working to
work on that publicly so that other
people with similar projects can either
learn or actually join two together text
so we can work together a bit more
cohesively and then that will expand as
we get more projects we can sort of
start to see how we can really live in
game B check to see how we can take
these kinds of projects for example mine
and Bentley's are sort of their you know
some similar in like they both belong to
the sense making space and in a game a
we'd probably be in competition but in
game be part of the goal is to see how
can we actually work together as a
benefit
to get more out of it than we would
being competitive in gaming yes that is
our current project but together Tec is
also a user cooperative for technology
so how do we create technology that
helps us live and gave me how do we
create omni win solutions and figuring
out all of that the governance the
financing marketing and so our first
project of the project we're focusing on
right now is the meta project of
projects because it helps do that but
yes that together Tech is a was a tech
cooperative and then we started to
calling it like a solutions cooperative
because that is what we're focusing on
is creating solutions with technology
yeah and just to add that I think it's
shoot I just started talking and
everything left yeah so it's an
opportunity to practice and play at game
be amusing you know are building things
that we want in that space trying to be
non-competitive and then also it's an
opportunity to find a way to make a
living off of well make a living while
practicing game be outside of game a as
much as possible and then you know just
because many of us like using tech their
lives or can build it that's why it's
been tech focused so far but then yeah
as jublee said you know anything that
that solves problems and gets the world
closer to a game be space yeah in my
mind it's kind of like as it as the
entry point to any kind of projects
where you can come find all kind of
resources in people people that have
resources be that material resources or
abilities where we can coordinate and
then
just to get our move technology forward
yeah all in that game be space alright
awesome I felt like a little bit like an
ibn cafe I liked it
which is my project I guess for bringing
projects to that at a project - idea
cafe in communication peace does anyone
have anything they'd like to add to the
agenda I kind of put a bunch of things
on it just cuz it was like but well yeah
but but I'm you know I think if people
have ideas we can sort of add as we go
yes so we did the first part which was
just introducing it together Tech is
then the next piece I had here was
talking about them in a project how do
we we this is where I was confused from
last week and forgot to re-watch the
board meeting which was on the crab
democracy channel and now we're kind of
starting afresh anyway so how do we want
our Friday medians to go do we want this
to be again moving together tech forward
like moving the meta project together or
do we want it to be a mastermind
bringing our projects here so we can
showcase what that looks like to help
each other or is there a third option
and then and my mind is mostly the first
one so like the III we need and we'll
end up with sort of multiple shows on
this channel for things like you know
project raising and the the
brainstorming but I think having a show
and maybe it doesn't end up being weekly
the actual final board meeting but just
sort of do something as similar to a
game a board meeting you know a
corporate world where you're covering
the same important aspects and then we
can add whatever we want because the
idea is what does a board meeting look
like in game B it's sort of what I'm
trying to think of so whatever that ends
up being however that that looks I think
that's the goal for this meeting even if
it gets moved around to different
timeslots etcetera whatever we're
calling me together tech board meeting I
think should have some elements of that
sort of like corporate governance but
where we wouldn't need to worry about
you know the profit-seeking aspects and
stuff like that a lot of game a would
and there's probably going to be some
extra thing
is that you never talk about an
eight-game a board meeting that will
come up here yeah oh that's what else
ascribe to the agenda train will come
forth so I drew you or you were saying
the board the meta project right as
opposed to the mastermind on our
individual projects right for Friday
right yeah and I think it's where
possible we should probably try to
emphasize like the individual meetings
so mastermind we can you don't sort of
define what that is and what the goal is
and then if it moves around it's still
just the the mastermind reading and so
this at least for the first session is
just called the together tech board
meeting and so I think those are
separate and be mastermind like I think
that's kind of my understanding here
mastermind that's sort of like the bolt
conversation that Jubilee has in mind
which wants to be able to have a hundred
people come together and split out into
different groups and figure things out
and then no not necessarily it's more
like you and Bentley it could be either
you and Bentley and whoever else has a
sense making project talking about sense
making projects or people coming
together and talking about marketing on
their projects right it sounded like a
but only in for people because it's
gonna be on YouTube and then I would
love to have conferences or APIs pull it
off but we need way more people before
that okay I've been calling those co-op
councils cuz that didn't like that seems
a bit more okay
descriptive you know I'm a my mind but
I'm open to new ideas yeah I mean
languages ELISA yeah naming things in a
way that people understand what they are
without explaining it and not using game
a language right possible tasks yeah
well I think you can use it as long as
you're sort of repurposing it like you
know a board meeting is I mean it's not
really game a but I kind of is you okay
so um to revamp from last week I believe
Adriel you said you're gonna start the
YouTube channel which you did I don't
remember bently said anything specific
that he was taking on and I was saying
on the questionnaire which I did said
nope
yeah I don't think I had anything so how
do you know I did send out the
questionnaire we had 10 responses which
is awesome especially since like 7 of
those responses came overnight like I
posted 11 p.m. I woke up to seven
responses and I think the only reason we
don't have a lot more than that is that
the algorithm makes it disappear right
people aren't constantly commenting on
it then it disappears and so there are
four of us all in the game be space and
we can boost each other's posts by
commenting and liking them and that's
should be what we're doing so that
people who want to see these things like
we're probably I think the biggest game
B project it's there like anyone can
come participate can bring your project
to it
it's Omni when it's Angie by Burress
it's all of all of the things on they
aren't actually game be right that
aren't like the wiki and those those
types of things and so I think it is
ethical to boost the posts so that they
they go there you can find them admits
the ones that people are commenting how
is this game be well you just made a
game B by commenting on it and bringing
the algorithm and so yes especially with
the questionnaire and if we write if I
write up a post after for the next show
to boost it to just comment on it and
have a conversation with each other on
there so that people will see it if that
feels right to people
I mean yep and that's something where
that might actually be a part of the
meta project sort of one of these
strategies is in these situations we
recommend you know like for example if
Billy and I have a sense making up
council and we have opposed to do with
that then the people in that council
might you know go and like it and share
it and the whole thing where it's in
each group the goal is to increase
visibility or things that actually have
a purpose yeah and also like even on
your Twitter or on other the same thing
sorry I'm about the the post that you
posted before where you collected the
projects
let's spreadsheet
um which also people open the
spreadsheet but I don't necessarily then
comment on the post
um and so that post itself it tends to
disappear unfortunately which it might
also be good for posts like that word
them in a way that we're also
encouraging people that do it right like
hey tell your form and then add a
comment saying what you did blow up a
bus actually I think you did that didn't
you saying like add your add to comment
so that meeting who it is or one of the
question ones yeah I basically was like
if you agree comments if you don't agree
call me and to people because yeah
exactly that I didn't put it for the
algorithm for the questionnaire itself
it was for something else that was just
a questionnaire I think you did
something it wasn't a diversity um that
was the question whether we want to have
different topics for to talk about every
week or did you ready a cafe as more of
a incentive for people getting to thank
you bonus for being my memory and it is
it's hard to stay at the top of the game
be it just in the algorithm and those
kind of things like I don't wanna have
to post a new thing for the project like
go to this one and fill out the project
I also don't know what we're doing with
that questionnaire no but it's filled
out by ten people we should also really
maybe make more use of the links on the
site like this I think document so that
I don't have it open right now but
documents and all sort of Vicki maybe um
to put put our links there I'm so that
it's in a more stable yes I think that
totally makes sense like actually all a
different like sticky content see if you
can get added they're like different
things that makes a lot of sense come
you know on the wiki I think that leads
to I I'm there just to participate in
conversations because I don't actually
know how to do it but if someone can
walk me through how to not necessarily
pin the four of us I can get somebody in
the wiki page to walk you through how to
post those things than having more like
our YouTube contents in any of the
projects we are
it's not just our YouTube channel it is
project raising and the whenever we're
calling the masterminding the cooperate
I can't ruin your name what's party drew
co-op councils yeah and updating it
right as new things come out right maybe
the new show that I think will be
popular in the game be space cuz that's
the point is to find something that's
popular I just think it'd be really fun
to sit for an hour and brainstorm ideas
the tech and solve an actual problem
without actually needing to make it I'm
coming to a new which is that is the
show idea the new show but we're not
there yet another project so the
questionnaire what do we do with it now
is on the agenda because I honestly
don't know you thought we made it and
then the mentor project like how do we
actually get people not to project
raising because I don't think it's that
hard but to have someone get their
project raised is easy to have people
come participate in raising other
people's projects and how do we
coordinate the co op ER councils how
does that actually work like what are
the ideas for Murphy right yeah and like
how you get from having one person in a
topic to okay but the second and third
when do you start those councils how do
we categorize them as a whole thing to
do with how do we actually get those up
and going and how do we Julian show to
the people who filled out the
questionnaire and said yes they want to
participate right yeah so I think the
next steps are reaching out to them but
also one thing I think we should do is
take that data and and put it in the
game be wiki and clean up their prod
over the project page basically unless
they don't want us to but which I think
they want contributors so I think it'd
be an issue
and put all that data in a more
manageable format would be one thing to
do with it
on that no I've been playing with sort
of like the two different versions of
the app I'm trying to build some kind of
like a
member portal involve bubble and nack
and sort of playing with the tools there
so I think we could have something early
days in one of those two areas pretty
soon and also building an app right now
in bubble with a sign-in page and login
and everything so I'll be pretty
familiar with it I spent 8 hours on it
yesterday and ok 4 hours on it today so
I might so I might be a little quicker
but also I don't want to duplicate the
wiki I mean we're talking about that
there's okay to have duplication of
things but I hate duplication so yeah I
think for the most part the wiki it's
too like even though it's editable it's
too static and it's not really great for
data it's great for you know like an
article the some of the people in the
wiki their vision because badly and I
were part of the call us I'm sauce
Friday right that was with you know um
is more of what we're talking about with
together tech not necessarily the meta
project and how to facilitate projects
but how to do more of the cooperation
and I like creating game be through the
nose like oh that's more of a platform
to me or social media but that sounds
like the to kind of like are pretty
interweb in it just started at the wiki
versus starting with yeah and I think
there will if we're able through there
should be some overlap like what
whatever app is built and bubble or neck
or whatever probably should have some
like out linking to various pages of the
wiki like hey here's the topic there's
not like because both programs are
fairly simple as far as like you can
just sort of meet the after is not a lot
of sort of you know built-in help but
you can probably add links that will say
if you're trying to use this stage and
have questions click here in the map to
page on the wiki that talks about that
thing so I'd really want are you hoping
to build you mentioned a login system
but what what are you hoping to have in
bubble which which idea is this to start
with this is the list of projects this
is going to be the projects that are
sort of listing who's involved now what
help they need and then for members to
be able to sign in and say you know
here's my project if I have one here's
the things I'm interested in here's the
projects in that space
are looking for help from somebody with
my skill set and then being able to pair
those up and now you don't have people
all apply or or contact the project to
actually start pairing people who don't
have projects or who do and just would
also like to help with projects with the
projects that they can join so it just
found that posted I mentioned in the
beginning on Facebook about high low
high low calm and that sounds like a
little bit like what you are describing
as anyone by any chance looked at is
that H ILO h hy lor and yes oh that one
yeah it seems like you can have a group
and then in that group like a community
and then in that community different
projects and then different members and
then people can basically sign up to
work on different projects or so and
communicate and collaborate so I spend
only five minutes on Dennis I'm not and
it's it's pretty empty at the moment
before you dive into the bubble thing is
it an app because high-lows also seems
to be a I drop hy l Oh calm yeah yeah
I'm there the easiest way to organize
and grow your community
so I mean that looks good one of my
eventual goals is returning this into
sort of a few different days where you
end up with like your projects that have
the things that they're looking for all
the different live streams so people can
sort of see what types of content like
this are available and they can see you
know the schedule all that kind of thing
but I can make things about both bubble
and nack is there platforms that let you
build right so you can build your own
features can someone point me to the
actually
Tube channel that we are like fun yes
together tech and if you actually if I
search together duck here I have it here
together Tecton I find only heaps of
videos that have to get on taking the
title did you see it's in the private
shot here I'll adapt in case someone is
watching and so yeah what was your
difference to high low that you I mean
like high low is probably an
out-of-the-box product that like we
could sign up for and start using for
the expected purpose right now but I
don't think it's like what you call a
drag-and-drop development platform and
it's a not a no code application
creation so you're on the side that some
of the some of the functionality we want
wouldn't be supported in something like
a high low or a mighty Belle groups
which I imagine what is what hallows
like where they're pretty much kind of a
social media replacement with some
different it's not really social media
yeah and I can't even see from this how
they support this project
but yeah so I imagine if if we want
custom functionality I don't think
high-low would which would be like well
like you know having a project to
resource matching system so you could
have like these are the projects these
are the different types of projects
there are and I here's my here's what
I'm interested in and then it would
created a matching of the projects to
figure out which ones I should join now
we're not
that sort of thing I don't think how I
would support that no which is exactly
like there's so many amazing projects
out there but if we don't own them and I
don't mean the four of us I mean
humanity right like we don't own it we
can't improve it we can't make it work
for our and as a person who wants to
work on multiple projects I don't want
either I've briefly brief lived a pilot
so I don't know if they do what I want
them to do
which is as an individual I want to see
all the projects and I want my dashboard
right I want to be able to like their
designs so together Tech could have a
community but but reasons court couldn't
use that same community wiki lecture
couldn't use that same community and so
we're not we're having to solve the
marking and finance everything problem
again and again and again for every
project as opposed to creating the
matter project that is like wait if
somebody's interested in reasons for
their probably also interested in
collection and they might do you know
like a couple hours of work for creating
a logo for you and a couple hours of
works for you if that's their the thing
they're good at and they wanted to work
with with who and it makes it easier to
volunteer or get paid depending on for
the various projects and as a user as a
set of months to be involved I want to
be able to have my dashboard with all of
those not sign-in and sign-out for wiki
lection and four reasons for which seems
to but all of them are because they're
all about decentralization even when
were talking about the wiki lecture for
game B they're like and then we can sell
it to nuns in Florida like I want to
have one app but like that's just my
preference or if we want to compete with
Facebook and I think we do want people
then like creating it for the individual
user as opposed to the community but
with the community in mind is what you
kind of need to do so I want to be if I
wanted to be part of the nuns in Florida
and Big B I want mine to be all of that
like it is on Facebook right I don't
have to sign it and sign out to join
Gabey or my parenting groups or my
acoustic neuroma one I could just be on
Facebook high/low may actually have that
type of grouping smooth some of the text
on there kind of implies that you a
person can be a member of multiple
groups without
out setting in but what I have it
confirmed that briefly looking at it it
does seem like if we weren't trying to
go to the next step i lo would
definitely be a great first step because
it is the member community it does it
probably has you know 80% of the stuff
that we'd want on day one but a big part
of it is just the ability to sort of
tweak it as you're build exactly yeah I
guess I think of it more yeah that first
stepping stone that right for example it
could be used in order for us to UM
stopped the meet our project and get
people together and down with those
people together build our own
alternative if we decided that is indeed
necessary I guess the question is like
if for some reason no miss someone
hadn't heard of Facebook and they or may
not like they joined Facebook to be in
game B and then they're on Facebook so
they join all the other ones is it like
that where if Adriel brings people to
the table for wiki lection are they also
made available two reasons for right and
all the other ones or does it just so
happen that if that if both Adriel and
bentley get me to sign up for their
individual projects I do believe get to
be on both of them but it's not me
Jubilee signing up for my collection and
then because I know I'm interested in
that they also show key reasons for
right and anyone involved in it can
write like are they giving me community
or do I have to create my own what I
think I understand what you're asking
and what I'm hearing is is it like
Facebook where you sign up for one
account and as many companies as want to
sort of sign up for their own page or
community and you can choose what to
join or is it like Google Drive or where
you need an account to participate but
you can't go and find any document
somebody has to sort of share it with
you to invite you to work together even
though you're in the same ecosystem
there isn't it yeah until you explicitly
say let's you know sign up and work on
or like discord
write discord you have to be invited you
can't really search them and do like
it's and yet at the same time Facebook
you can only kind of do that if there's
like money like I know I want an
acoustic neuroma group good I could go
search that out but
it's not gonna tell me hey we noticed
you at an acoustic Roman did you know
there's a community around that like and
there's this community that's talking
about brain tumors or you know what I
mean like this it's not their idea to
make money they're an ant to make my
life more connected right or to help
together tech or game be succeed any
more than any other company
yeah it looks like they do have very
similar goals so I would say that they
so they definitely do have posts from
all your communities at once so you you
you know it's more like Facebook in that
way they may not have the surfacing or
finding of communities although we could
theoretically do that separately
temporarily I said I see the only real
reason to start using this is if we
choose to get off of Facebook well we're
not really on Facebook like I mean we
are we use messenger but do you mean
like like we don't even have a Facebook
group right forty other tech for game B
we do and that's kind of part of it
right like maybe as our pool of people
to be interested and we could also use
that pool to create together tech but
like unless people join together tech
they're not part of that pool and it's
the same problem if we join high-low
right like are we bringing people to
that to be part of that community in
connection yeah this our first yeah go
ahead
it might be good if someone and yonus
you may want to take this on actually
sign up as a member see what you see and
like is it Facebook ish where you can
just sign up as a member and see all the
communities and search for them or is it
more community-centric where you're
signing up as a part of a community
that's all you see to sort of start with
and then as you get invited you can just
reuse that that login does that make
sense yeah it makes sense I am signed up
already but I am apparently the only
person there now did you need to like
sort of crater on space or is it like
Facebook we're here to stop now a member
of hi
and there's all these different
communities that now you can join no
it's I mean I think you see all the
communities and then when you go into
one community you see all their projects
I'm not sure whether you have to be part
of that community first before you
actually see the projects but yes I
think it is quite open but it's hard to
really tell and verify because it's the
only person I don't know whether there
are actually other communities or it
might be that there are but they are
hidden and I'm actually not the only
person there which well I mean it order
to sign up you have to hit a button that
says start a community right there is no
creator down so you notice I think you
had to create a community and maybe
they're just terminology which is a big
problem because how do we get like I
guess then you create a community then
you should probably invite people but
then you have to invite people with I
guess we can probably post a discussion
around specifically a silo at a moment
um I can keep an eye on it I look more
into it but so what I hear out of all of
this is that we want to have at least
soonerlater at least this our own
version of this where people can
interact and find each other in the way
that we want to shape it and yeah where
do we want to exactly so we have as much
control over the roadmap as possible so
we don't you know like oh they're
missing a certain feature can we have
that yeah well think about that in five
years which and to that point I'm not
100% sure whether that is
at least in the stage where where we are
right now the right way for what because
there are so many tools that will
probably facilitate the first steps
already that and you know it for us to
get to the point now okay good on the
other Bentley and it really research
that you played with bobland you could
create something like that right now I'm
imagining like it would take a year
until we get to that point but if you
say what functionality if you want if
you want to replace Facebook groups or
high-low it would still take several
months but I don't think that we have a
huge value and in that I think the main
thing we want to do which isn't done
anywhere which is a a skill and time
matching with projects I don't think
high-low has that yet I think if the
skill matching with projects with
necessarily the time scheduling I'm not
sure that's the thing it might have
skill matching with in a community which
I guess if we had a single community
with multiple projects then yeah maybe
that would work and it should always be
free but that is a project maybe not but
then well there's my place sorry
whatsoever yeah that's one thing that
job it does see like sign up for free
with the yeah but does it say that's
free yeah nothing is ever free game B's
not even free yeah if you're not paying
your you're the product right now yeah
cuz we're living in a game a well yeah
in game age we're not paying her the
process into it we probably yeah I mean
to you know at this point if I need to
look at it see what does functionality
is and see what overlap this is because
even if we don't end up using it it's
it's good to know how much overlap we
have
and if we do end up using it maybe
that's one less thing we have to build
although we do eventually have a concern
on living if it ends up being kind of a
game a product then eventually may want
to replace it but right I don't know if
it does everything what we want and yeah
exactly if it can allow us to focus on
other things and it can do 80% of what
we want to do then it's probably good
job yeah so I would be interested to
find out about the the skill matching
sort of across projects like if we say
here's a skill you know for marketing
and a skill for I don't know finance in
one project say I need help with
marketing a different project and say I
help with finance and their new member
signs up and says I'm good at finance
doesn't highlight oh go over there yeah
people find a purpose so um okay I can
set that cost around high-low has
apparently been acquired by holo
we already I think many of us are well
holo
I'm already there also in the game be
space ish um a little bit not officially
but has been often referenced here um
the holo chain hollow chain yeah they
are it's based on the whole of chain
anyway I can send send of the post
around where they say more about it and
base the firsts first lion and there is
something
is that it's a web and mobile app to
help communities and groups communicate
and collaborate more effectively and I
so it sounds like they are also in the
beginning stage a little bit of you know
what they're doing and I think it would
make sense for us to try to collaborate
with them actually in our and see what
their vision is maybe and and what we
want to do it it sounds like we are
probably going in the same direction at
least the difference is if their whole
load chain that means they're
decentralized it means their block chain
which means every one thing has to be
that nail before they apply that hammer
and at least my vision for together tech
is like will be own it together we can
figure out a cola like if blockchain is
the way but it's like like and this
doesn't mean we don't reach out to them
they'll have a conversation because I
think that's what we do but then they
want to decentralize they want your
community to be separate in this
community to be separate and they don't
care that that you get one one dashboard
they don't know how to even know if they
see the vision because it's like every
like everything needs to be set
decentralized so that we're safe as
opposed to right but we're not powerful
then like there's something be said for
doing things together as long as it's
done transparently and I I don't think
that that being on the holo train
necessarily means that you are separate
so they are quickly ways where you can
still have you know the the interaction
and linking up of things and so it
doesn't necessarily exclude put me into
more are you able to send invites or
anything yours
like how do you add something to it
maybe I'll check it out if you do find
the way if you can message me on
Facebook all you know send you my email
or whatever it needs to send me the end
but I'd be interested to sign up as a
member just to see what it looks like
all right is there anything pressing
right now for together - Oh what was
that
here's together tech just open any
window with us like we're going to we
talked about the algorithm that we're
gonna go and like the questionnaire post
we haven't really talked about Rick
she's gonna do with that besides the
winky put it on but we kind of need
permission like someone permission
so maybe posting that in the wiki game
the Facebook group of like hey we have
this questionnaire how do we get more
people to fill it out and how do we use
it on the wiki right yeah I'm wondering
if a we could project within the first
time would also be good check with them
I don't think I don't think the one
people asking permission before you go
in or do things I think they want people
to be she is my they have their projects
right like how do we not dismantle that
and add what they have that is use that
we don't have right because we have 10
people have been filled it out we don't
have 100 people filling it out or you
know what I mean everyone in the game be
space that's part of the algorithm is to
go in boosters so that hopefully we do
get more I feel like if we have 25
projects so be easier to be like hey
these are all baby projects they have
invented them but hey that's part of it
is how do we met them what is GABP we're
all figuring that out is it Omni when it
Santa Barbara is who owns it can I be
involved in it it's in a podcast you
know like what is what are the Wow what
are the labels at the top how do we
organize this and that's part of being
part of kind of that conversation less
about permission and more just about
like how do we not undo it you've done
and add our stuff to it yeah I would I
would think and then the wiki it'd be
quicker to just go and suggest the
change I think there's a way to draft a
change and then have them come back
because I think 9 I think there's you
know they're just gonna accept or
whatever we do
unless it's horrendous and they're
pretty swamped but I depend on you know
who ends up having time to do that okay
so yeah if someone couldn't just boost
the algorithm on the game be regular
Facebook group
search for me and then the questionnaire
was the one that was gained being quite
liked for projects of projects I don't
even what I said because it was like
four or five days ago like I think about
so I'll go add a comment just saying oh
hey I added wiki election like just
something simple like that which is what
I actually said to do in the thing I was
like and tell me who you are so I can
match you with your Facebook profile
because some people don't have the same
name and very few people commented um
which is fine and like people just don't
read they just start doing you know and
so it becomes like that's I want the
algorithm to work in our favor so
there's four of us and we can make that
happen
I have less power that because I'm the
one originally posted it right so and I
like things it doesn't necessarily
missed it not one I can like your guys's
posts like wiki like should I always
like it I don't know silly comments on
it maybe I should pause I might as well
but yes is there anything else for
together text specifically is this what
like what are we gonna do next week what
does this look like going forward or we
just so one of the things that I guess
there's two things one at some point I'd
like to actually start the co-op council
for four cents making so so badly and I
can start to sort of guys reason score I
mean from what the small amounts of
heard of it it does sound like there's a
fair amount of overlaps I'd be
interested to see how that conversation
goes and talking about that specifically
and then sort of the higher level
conversation that I think we're all
interested in to some extent which is
the conversation around trust like what
does the public mean or to trust an
organization well what does it need to
trust the other members of the
organization one of the need to trust
the final product like all these
different things that I think for pretty
much all the projects I've heard there's
some element of even if you know you're
just making some widgets what do people
need in order to trust the company
making them yeah like what it's you sir
what I how would I like not really why
would I find really far but then if I
did finding this it's like
trust and marketing and Finance are
pretty key central conversations need to
have on all the projects like how do you
get it made financing how do you keep it
going how do you get people on it so
it's sustainable is to get the money on
it and then how with that how do we open
that trust is a huge piece of that yeah
and that's really one that we're not
gonna be well I think that's it's just
not it's like exactly it's all like all
the things that you just listed do is
become topics of did this meeting I
would say probably not I would say that
might be me that might be like one of
the you know if we don't have enough
projects for project raising that one
might alternate between like project
raising and you know the meta project
like brainstorming yeah okay you know
that session on that on trust whatever
channel that fits into I just think of
all of them this one isn't it and I
think the brainstorming protect probably
isn't it yeah there was also so one of
the people whose interest in doing
project raising is an Australian Richie
and like this type slot is way too early
for him if you like
you know 3 a.m. before I got this time
it's even I know it's early for us as
well but it's like even earlier which
feels weird because I'm a telescope but
I feel like that's different in our
country I also might just be confused
based on Murray Zealand isn't Australia
is right not the point um so that
wouldn't be moving project raising
consistently it would just be for people
who truly can't make that time period do
we want an alternative time period and
do we also vote this one and then just
have that one is let's say it monthly
we're gonna also have one it like 2 p.m.
our time right that works but like 2
p.m. our time on Saturdays once a month
Network other people to join and then if
we're doing I like the idea of
alternating a project phrasing for
someone else versus a meta project
raising for us right like where's the
one thing if that works
2:00 p.m. what time zone or is that just
a throwing around side of your two hours
or later so I think that before p.m.
what time is it now for you Bentley I
can I bring its 143 yes the two hours
later so it'd be 4 p.m. your time and
I'm not I just made that at the time
it's not that's not the timer she gave
me I just mean it has to be later in the
day so does that time work for you yes
okay I would think ideally he'd probably
want a bit later because I think that's
still like 6:00 a.m. so earlier the next
day so it'd be Sunday too so for me
actually right now is this meeting
starts at 8:00 for me so for him it's
two hours earlier than that's just start
at 8:00
I mean you're 23 hours I'm ahead
21 hours I think is this 9:00 a.m. for
up for Adriel and I and 11 a.m. for
Bentley no no what
sorry Wow I'm thinking project raising
something so sorry
yeah yeah so you know I was going there
yet what day is it project I think it's
6 6 p 6 a.m. I think it's like 4 a.m. so
yeah I think it would be better to move
it a little bit more than two hours
right it's 9 10 11 12 1 to 5 hours ahead
then normally is because that one is a 9
a.m. in the morning and then moving it
once a month for it to be to be honest
of people ok yeah so then I think 11 for
Jonas and 9 a.m. for that person which
seems yeah which I assume in some way
I'm so you can just ask him but it works
when I'm on three yeah yeah so do we
want to so we can have
the other week we could try it and say
hey we're going to raise our own project
the meta project every other week or we
can do it once a month whatever people
wants and then we can have project
raising raising other people's projects
and I think part of project raising
should also be an invitation meaning
what does that actually look like I
don't know to be part of the meta
project right like like come help us
participate in raising the meta project
on the other Saturdays but also if you
can make this meeting even if they're
just watching and commenting or you know
like what not a requirement but an
invitation
I think it'll actually be interesting
once we get enough people interested or
even some of us to sub out and be an
audience member I think it would be
interesting to try to interact that way
see how that works see how the comment
like has I have no idea what it's like
to be an audience member for a live
stream and how that worked and how that
interaction works and you know what it
feels like having to type your questions
and then seeing numbers like I'm not
sure I wasn't that in one of the earlier
ones I say just a chatter and it was
yeah you're always late with your
comments to whatever I say so yeah no I
think that's a good idea
we have other people to swap in to like
try it from the other side and say right
like this isn't I'm hoping this is game
B and it's like we figure out a way to
get a decentralized somewhat decision
making where it's like it's not for
people making a decision for everyone
it's bring your ideas for your project
how do we have an effective conversation
with a bunch of people how do we have a
collective governance with a bunch of
people not as much as you know part of
me wants ownership part of me wants to
make billions of dollars off of it but I
don't I want it to work I want a tech
company that helps humanity create Omni
win solutions and that is easier like a
board meeting a board is effective and
so we don't throw the baby out with the
bathwater
have a board but how many people can the
board old fine if it can hold all our
members we can figure that out I think
once it's actually like an entity we
have to find out like is there certain
things or if the organization does
something wrong the board members are
the ones that are liable and so we have
to figure out how whatever entity
together Tec ends up as a GIF it's a
cooperative a society or what the board
one might actually be a group of people
that like that one's not a swappable
because these are the people who if you
know together in fact bricks the law
they're the ones going to jail so
they're the ones that can you know that
have the veto power like I know you guys
voted for that but I don't want to go to
jail so no right right and that is how
it works I know the board is probably
just like any other board responsible
but also the membership owns it and
they're responsible to the board like it
or names so yeah the idea is that to
some degree the board is less
responsible than in other regular
corporations because we're transparent
and because we're doing it in that way
where it's like anyone like if it's the
public suing us
yes we're responsible if it's our
membership suing us no like you're just
as responsible right I'd like clean that
out at legal terms look like you could
have also so much worried about like the
suing so much as the like there's going
to be a lot of people in positions of
power that if this works are gonna be
fairly upset with us and we'll do things
you know so it's trying to make sure
that like wherever possible we know what
bounds were playing within if we can say
if it's a membership driven co-op then
you know the board isn't as liable or at
all then it might be completely fluid
yeah yeah and we have to work within
game a to create game that's yeah
figuring all of that out and doing it
transparently which puts a bit more risk
and less risk at the same time by
guaranteed we're gonna pierce the
corporate veil it's nearly impossible to
not when you have my board meetings and
so that puts us financially responsible
but like in no way is there any finances
on the line you in any way so how we
need to have the conversations before
that happens of how don't you pierce the
corporate veil in a live board meeting
when we're board members spitballing
ideas it's like or we can serve you know
doing this thing and someone's like oh
actually that's
we know when you're talking about
piercing the corporate veil do you mean
like the fact that most board meetings
for corporations are closed and so it's
opening that up and when you incorporate
as a corporation you're the corporation
is the thing taking everything on right
so they're the ones take financial risk
are the ones to go in the legal risk and
since you can't send a corporation to
jail unless the board does actually
illegal things you it's the like entity
that's kind of tried not the individuals
but if you pierce the corporate veil
which is like me be like Jubilee is
doing instead of together Tech is doing
and even literally just saying it in
that way like is can be enough right and
so you're effectively incorporated for
no reason because now you're completely
right but yeah exactly so if it's like a
monetary thing you would see the
corporation because the corporation has
more money but like with the whole the
oxycontin the like those lawsuits
there's actually more members that have
been going to jail cuz they've been like
oh we found out that you knew what you
were doing and and it's that to make
money and kill people off to jail you go
right right and so that's like when you
do illegal activity as a board
you've already pierced the veil but if
you do things that are that like in
between like let's say you you create a
product and you didn't do it maliciously
but it needs to be recalled that you
recall it that people died the board
doesn't go to jail right it's like no
that was within our capacity we did
everything we could we found no
insurance we have all of this but there
can still be a point where if they can
prove you pierce the corporate veil but
it's actually the board that goes to
jail and not the corporation that's then
sued into because it's but the whole
reason corporations were created was to
not pass that financial and legal risk
on to the board members and on to the
people like the difference if you know
wow sole proprietorship or a partnership
and a corporation is that is that you're
not actually the limited that's the part
where you no longer have limited
liability once you've pierced it okay is
that actually a term like in that in
that space Oh
and so and I don't know exactly what
that looks like but I remember reading
all about about it in my reading days so
I did we only have like eight minutes
left I just wanted to bring up the idea
for the new show and kind of get the
okay to try it and run with it which is
creating an hour show weekly I don't
know when it will be that is basically
just problem solving solutions with tech
but without ever creating anything so
let's say you know you had a bunch of
people together and talk about food and
what you're currently doing what's
currently being done for food what we
want it what would we want to keep the
same what is good about our current
system for food and what is bad about
her for ancestor for food what could it
look like in game be here in 10 years in
the future and then what could we do now
right if we had a hundred thousand
dollars and ten thousand people what
would be possible because then that show
KC and I think for the regular everyday
public one they could be involved in
having that conversation they don't need
to have a technical degree right to be
talking about that and just that there
are solutions at all of these different
places and that's where my mind wants to
Kiko like that is basically why I'm
creating together tech is so that I can
sit and have conversations on how to
create solutions and so to just do that
I think that's great
I did want to give a little feedback I
think you might even just say come up
with solutions and just leave out the
with tech I mean I know all the
solutions end up having some sort of
tech a lot of people think digital
solutions which I just I don't think you
need that qualifier but I'm not in tech
right great
no idea how to code it but like can save
the world no problems because if we're
not bound like things like the trust
conversation might actually be that it
might actually hit there if it's not
solely about tech and it's about like
trying to solve problems because part of
the trust conversation there there will
be some tech there will be some like you
know what how does the corporation
operate one of the
the corporate values or however that
conversation goes undoubtedly some of it
will be tech but I think end goal is an
inherently tech or not tech it's just
yeah
like the idea cafe we're like us in no
way have to join in right it's just its
own channel in its own it will be on
this channel but is it something that
any of you desperately want to
participate in I like America because I
can't have it on the weekends it can't
be something that's on the weekend
because I've already dedicated this time
and I have a kid and I have all week to
do things but not necessarily on the
weekends but I'm open to doing it early
in the morning like 6:00 a.m. so it's
before work for like you or I mean
that'll make an 8 a.m. for you mentally
so even possibly earlier which me but
like I can get up at 5 a.m. once a week
and have a conversation how to create a
better world
so it's it's not it's coordinating the
time or it could be a floating time I
don't know my schedules pretty flexible
I and I it sounds like something I'd
like to participate although I'm getting
easily getting to the point where
overcommitted
yeah I mean it might work maybe to start
with like it sounds like because it's
not tech and it's more just about trying
to solve problems maybe it's becomes the
alternate timeslot in the project
raising so we got project raising this
project raising this until we get more
of an audience we could figure out what
people like what people are watching and
then figure out oh look we have a huge
audience for this Oh half them are in
Australia let's do two sessions let's do
one you know men and one later so that
we can start to yeah especially we don't
have to like the four of us don't have
to be in both of them but I yeah yeah
totally and is it you'll end up with
like moderators were probably one of us
will but I'm fine with either so it's
yeah I mean I'm good with that if if you
guys are gonna thought like it would be
instead of doing the meta projects we're
doing this or it could be project
raising project raising one meta project
a month and then one this a month but I
also want to be doing this week like for
me like how but that doesn't mean like
we get out of the week
and once a month then on Monday people
have a lot of people wanting to do
project raising no but I haven't put it
up in a while last time like I oh
there's someone more next week tomorrow
and then Richie wants to do one and I
think you wanted to do one for reasons
for right but we don't I haven't mind
anyone up I think that still broadly
plenty more if I remember the comments
there were there were quite a few
projects and I can't imagine that you've
gone already through all of them but
yeah there was a few at the beginning
that yeah contacted them in the other
aren't interested they never got back to
me other people who I have contacted and
so I think I would need to post it you
need to get more to kind of one put the
algorithm to just get it better and it's
just kind of Marini them what we're
doing like hey you bring an aspiration
and doing this but also that invitation
piece is like coming to be part of like
what could we do for you and what can
you do for us mm-hmm I think if there is
any kind of a lot we can also breathe as
a previous projects because it's not
like a project just needs to get and
freeze once if you rigged it once you
solve that problem great what's your
next problem because there's not my
people we want to do so here what I mean
instead of getting a new project every
time to go and have three-peat ones for
that very reason
yeah so I with all of that I mean that
sounds like that's also a thing that has
a lot of content I know we already
discussed this but maybe that should be
every week instead of every other week
and then thing else who want to do go at
a different time for the like the
revisiting the the reasons no just just
the project ratings and the revisiting
project Racing's because I think we
talked about alternating it with
something else right and I'm suggesting
we don't alter paid it with something
else the issue is I'm fine with that
except then you can't be on the weekends
I can move it yes what's the other
project that we're gonna alternate it
with the matter project good like so
what are we together so what are we
doing with this time then
yeah we can alternate this I'm not sure
that we need a board meeting every week
or a mini every week so I think Ord
meaning meta projects every other week
so having like a brainstorming here's
and so therefore how do we decide what
our aspiration is for that week and then
like next we could talk about trust
right or do that and then that's what
then the other of the new show that I
just talked about could happen whenever
you're available okay cuz I could also
put that out to project B there's there
is like there's already four of us and
we're already the four phases that are
both or when you want to say well the
join like project raising and this right
so I can only this channel needs to be
all of like us right just like us so
it's like bringing other people on board
like this is more of an idea cafe type
thing of like what are you currently
doing for food and how do we actually
create something that sparks a
conversation where we're coming up with
a oh cool I want I want to like get in
the realm of possibility and hope
outside I'm flying within that hour
right like hey we actually solved
something if we had $10,000 or sorry ten
ten thousand people and a hundred
thousand dollars we could make this and
then like the channel getting to ten
thousand it's not different it's
difficult but it's not that difficult if
it's an engaging conversation that
people want to watch and participate in
and then it's actually possible to say
hey do we want to actually make this
thing you just created the project you
know to me that sounds kind of like it
almost makes sense to alternate with
project raising because that's kind of
pre project raising that's like project
raising is you have an idea you know
what you want to go you're trying to do
it and you need help and this is like
your so you know here's kind of how we
got to our projects but on a new idea I
mean the thing with project raising is
it's not hard to find people but it is
hard to find people to participate
what like to actually do the raising at
the project do you have a requirement of
you could participate twice before you
get your project raised and this could
be part of the participation right like
you don't need to feel like you're gonna
be responsible for cube spawn if it
fails or don't I mean like it's like
we're just figuring out food for the
world like just that we're just thicker
don't world peace or just snip all in
here that's where it is nothing that
open to all those options so yep all
right well I don't want to wait till
next week to actually put something out
there maybe community so are we just
leaving it with me I'll either do every
other week or even this timeslot a new
time slot or right no not the Friday
that's our meta project I mean let's go
ahead and throw out the general
problem-solving as to be a future
project raising slots the only thing
that's probably creasing or that's the
meta project that would alternate with
this times log like for the trust
conversation for example well I wasn't
talking about the trust conversation but
okay what we're talking about about the
solving problems problem solving like
the news show which the trust
conversation could be one of but I feel
like we actually don't want to start
with the dress conversation was not
there like solving a problem but that
was the marketing part of projects yeah
like the meta project but that's it I
think it fits with minute yeah that made
sense because it's also it's focusing on
the project but if we're asking like
regular everyday people what you trust
then it's kind of probably how do we
solve the problem of trust in politics
how do we solve the problem of my shots
and then recreating something from the
ground up as opposed to a drill ask and
how do I get you to trust being wiki
lecture right so it could be like a
dress through different right back okay
that makes sense so we're saying to
start with it's sort of just a meta
project part and what does a project
need to consider where trust is
concerned in general and then certain
projects might have specific challenges
yeah and so we're gonna do a project
raising so this week we have someone
tomorrow so I said a week from tomorrow
we can do this we can do a project
raising sorry I probably solve a project
raising around like following this
format and see how that works like a big
exclaiming huh sorry could just probably
call
a problem raising and a project or
everything a problem or anything like
that you're raising it up for a solution
yes I like it project raising problem
project problem project problem that you
know we can trial that and see because
then people can come and participate in
the rule is to be on in a new project
reason you have to have come and
participated in at least two problem or
project raisins is there a problem I'll
literally talk about any problem if we
can use technique solutions so is there
one that resonates with people could be
politics you know like I know that's not
very gamey but it also is game be it's
like how do we trust politicians how do
we actually create something that isn't
Bernie Sanders versus it's like no
matter what country you're in how do we
trust how do we create news stories how
do we like how do we do media coverage
or do we want nothing to do with your
projects and focus more on food shelter
something not have an overlap with my
current projects on that yeah because I
think that'll probably be like when we
start the coop councils that's what we
actually start talking about specific
like either co-op councils or project
rating that that's the 2d to talk about
like general challenges among that space
so like politics or you know the
decision-making and then like
specifically how does reason score plan
to solve this certain problem I have an
idea I'm gonna make a whatever pull and
post it on the gay people face it will
be three none of them OB politics and
it'll be whichever one resonates with
the most people will be able under that
and then we can also post the link to
that video there so the people will
watch if not participate what all right
and you notice you don't come to project
raises and now problem raises right
because they're too early for you yeah
often just too early I might sometimes
still come on if I'm really excited
about something but otherwise it might
be okay we'll just let me know if you
are gonna come after people have voted
because then I'll include you in the
metric of like we can only have up to
six people nothing this conversation I'm
not
all right I don't mind to just be in the
chat as well hum and listening
perfective wait up too many all right we
have definitely went over our in the
broadcast
all right behind YouTube
[Music]